Albert "Lael" Lum

(601) 618-7633 • alaellum@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Undergraduate computer engineering student currently committed as a contractor for the Navy for the next three years. Can program, tear down and repair electrical/mechanical devices, and have a firm understanding of computers and their components. I am looking for a work position that is mostly remote work, but I am still open to onsite work also. I prefer programming focused work.

Education

Mississippi State University (MSU) - Starkville, MS

August 2022 to December 2024

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering
- Overall GPA: 4.00/4.00

Hinds Community College (HCC) - Raymond, MS

January 2020 to May 2022

- Associate of Arts in Computer Engineering
- Overall GPA: 4.00/4.00

Work History

OIT Intern with Entergy - Grand Gulf Nuclear Station

June 2023 to July 2023

Performed and assisted with cyber security related tasks as well as troubleshooted technological issues

Landscaper, Self-employed - Port Gibson, MS

May 2016 to August 2022

Cared for lawns at a professional level and gave homeowners confidence in their own yards

• Utilized time management, critical thinking, and budget organization skills

Store Assistant, Ace Hardware – Port Gibson, MS

October 2018 to October 2019

Managed the store stock and assisted customers to deliver the best experience possible

- · Restocked shelves with weekly shipments involved understanding items, codes, and purpose of merchandise
- Assisting customers required knowledge of the function of equipment and ability to assist customers respectfully

Farmhand, Arnold Acres - Port Gibson, MS

October 2016 to May 2019

Baled hay, fed/branded cattle, and cared for livestock that benefited the local area with fresh grass-fed meat

- Worked with others as a team and did so under high stress situations
- Followed orders while made responsible for thousands of dollars' worth of equipment

Community Service

• Cleaned and repaired churches in current/distant communities (Port Gibson/Rodney, MS) November 2018 to February 2021

• Guided young children at churches in local area

June 2013 to July 2020

• Annual trash pickup participant in Port Gibson, MS

March 2015 to March 2019

• Formal fundraiser dinner for Vicksburg Center for Pregnancy Choices

May 2015 to May 2017

• Constructed handicap ramp for private citizen in Vicksburg, MS

October 2017

Honors and Recognition

Phi Theta Kappa member
February 2021 to Present

• Tau Beta Pi Elect

September 2023

• SMART Scholarship Awardee

April 2023

• Mathematics Award recipient for all HCC campuses

April 2023 April 2022

Physics & Computer Science Award recipient for all HCC campuses

April 2022

Skills

• Comfortable in C++ • Phone/Computer repair

• Engine/Transmission repair

• Computer technology

Soldering